<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sang Han</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sanghan.me/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sanghan.me/</id><updated>2014-05-05T23:24:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Digital Universe</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2014/05/digital_universe/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-05T23:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2014-05-05:blog/2014/05/digital_universe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In the digital universe, there are two kinds of bits:
bits that represent structures (differences in space)
and bits that represent sequence (differences in time).
Digital computers - as formalized by Alan Turing, and
developed by John von Neumann - are devices that translate
between these two species of bits according to definite&amp;nbsp;rules.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;George Dyson: Turing&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;Cathedral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary><category term="alan"></category><category term="turing"></category><category term="dyson"></category><category term="computing"></category></entry><entry><title>Amber</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2012/03/amber/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-21T23:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2012-03-21:blog/2012/03/amber/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before photography, I was a chemist.
I worked at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNF&lt;/span&gt; No
Before photography, I was a chemist.
I worked at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNF&lt;/span&gt; Novartis doing medicinal chemistry.
Those days were full of many great memories and I enjoyed my time there doing
chemistry. These days I am still in good contact with the people I met,
and worked with. Soon after I had left, word had spread to Yefen,
and she had become interested in getting a family portrait with her very young
1 year old daughter Amber. Of course, I was happy to oblige
and Yifen and I started to contact each&amp;nbsp;other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days with the advent of cheap digital &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SLR&lt;/span&gt; cameras,
it has become difficult to find the best photograph. Amber is Yifen&amp;#8217;s daughter,
and she is one of the cutest and happiest babies
I have had the chance to capture in still.
However photographing children is a completely different story.
Sometimes they&amp;#8217;re unresponsive and unintuitive to the camera facing them.
Sometimes they just want to play, and are difficult to approach strangers.
I was up to the challenge, and utilizing in conjunction my very broken
Mandarin Chinese and babytalk,
I wanted to capture the happy relationship between the family and their&amp;nbsp;child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber01" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber01.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber02" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber02.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber03" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber03.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber04" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber04.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber05" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber05.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber06" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber06.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber07" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber07.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber08" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber08.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber09" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber09.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber10" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber11" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber12" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber12.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber13" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber13.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Amber14" src="http://sanghan.me/img/amber/amber14.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Photography Tip #1 - What Camera Should I Buy?</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/06/2011-06-29-photography-tip-1-what-camera-should-i-buy/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-29T01:29:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-06-29:blog/2011/06/2011-06-29-photography-tip-1-what-camera-should-i-buy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So people have been asking me a lot of questions these days about
photography. One question in particular that I get almost every time is
about which cameras, lenses and other equipment they should purchase.
And a lot of times, I really don&amp;#8217;t feel like I can substantiate this
with an answer without first asking multiple questions myself.&amp;nbsp;Like,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you take pictures of? People? Are you the person among your
group of friends who is always documenting the moment? Does everyone
expect you to be the one uploading and tagging shots on&amp;nbsp;facebook??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landscapes? Are you always bringing your camera when going on that next&amp;nbsp;adventure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art? Is normal photography too mainstream? Are you trying to express
some creative impulse? Do you hang around coffee shops with large framed
glasses and an&amp;nbsp;ipad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of times photography is less about the equipment you own, and more
about the subject that you wish to put on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card (please don&amp;#8217;t
troll me about this). And in fact, you don&amp;#8217;t need to spend ridiculous
amounts of money to have the right camera. Most of the time, the best
camera is the one you&amp;nbsp;own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in order to give an answer to this small rant. I think the question
here is worded incorrectly. Most of the time, people ask about camera
equipment, not because they want to buy something, but because they have
a desire to take better pictures. In this case, I would recommend buying
a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FILM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAMERA&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;Sounds crazy, but it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with point-and-shoot cameras is in the name. The purpose is
to be able to point at a scene and just take a shot. Automation destroys
the desire to learn and makes photography less rewarding. So throwing
yourself into manual settings really opens up a new world for people. If
you can take a decent picture with a film camera, you will probably take
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMAZING&lt;/span&gt; ones in digital. Also, film bodies and lenses are dirt cheap.
You can pick them up from craigslist for &amp;lt;$100 and these used to be top
of the line professional&amp;nbsp;equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you a step in that direction, I would&amp;nbsp;recommend the Canon &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AE&lt;/span&gt;-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" src="/img/D3S_7456-1200.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_AE-1"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_AE-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find these on craigslist and ebay for $50 with a 50mm f/1.8 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FD&lt;/span&gt;
fixed focal length lens. The fixed focal length means that the lens
doesn&amp;#8217;t zoom. But this is more of an advantage. It causes you to think
more about composition and the quality of pictures are outstanding. You
can also purchase a variety of other &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FD&lt;/span&gt; lenses, zoom and fixed for dirt
cheap. You just have to remember one thing, make sure to buy&amp;nbsp;film!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this little rant. It&amp;#8217;s a lot of fun for me to talk to
others about photography. If anyone has any questions at all that they
would like me to answer, let me&amp;nbsp;know!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Camera"></category><category term="Photography Tips"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Canon AE-1"></category></entry><entry><title>San Deezy</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/06/2011-06-26-san-deezy/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-26T00:28:58-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-06-26:blog/2011/06/2011-06-26-san-deezy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Coming back to San Diego in the morning. Whoever is still around, I&amp;#8217;d
love to see&amp;nbsp;you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Photography Rant #1</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/06/2011-06-17-photography-rant-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-17T06:05:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-06-17:blog/2011/06/2011-06-17-photography-rant-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone learns to take good pictures by first taking bad ones. But we
first have to understand that creating the image which puts absolution
to the moment is somewhat of an arduous task. And in fact, most photos
fail to come close to meet this somewhat abstract criterion for a&amp;nbsp;Good&amp;nbsp;Photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although understanding this, most people will never admit to a bad
photo. They come up with cleaver reasonings to vindicate a shot and thus
first place a primal block on their chance of learning from their
mistakes. Working with some of these people, I&amp;#8217;ve heard some pretty good
excuses, most using the &amp;quot;creativity&amp;quot; moniker as a mental force field
against constructive&amp;nbsp;criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we really need to understand is that taking a bad photo is indeed a
good thing. Taking the underexposed 35 degree tilted, center focused
slightly blurry photo with major white balance problems is where most
people start. Eventually, we learn to focus, compose and the desire to
correct ourselves pushes us to the better&amp;nbsp;image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, from the back&amp;nbsp;of a thousand poorly taken photographs spurs an
image redemptive of each past failing exchange. But most of the time, we
just end up taking the shot and moving&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="photography"></category><category term="rant"></category><category term="image"></category><category term="composition"></category></entry><entry><title>Open Mind</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/06/2011-06-14-open-mind/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-14T03:57:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-06-14:blog/2011/06/2011-06-14-open-mind/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of an open mind is the same as of an open mouth, it&amp;#8217;s meant
to close on something. An open mind in pursuit of the truth, needs to
seek it out and eventually close on it, so that we can know what is&amp;nbsp;real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;G.K.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Chesterton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Journeys</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/04/2011-04-20-journeys/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-20T03:13:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-04-20:blog/2011/04/2011-04-20-journeys/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So looking back at these 4 years, I&amp;nbsp;reminisce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each person traverses a path laid out by their circumstance, made their
own completely separate and unique experience. Recounting, as for only a
wisp of time we share in a casual encounter. Listening to stories of how
we got here and where we wish to go. I&amp;#8217;ve realized, for a moment, we all
share in this same space. But soon we will depart as life&amp;#8217;s natural
trajectory unfolds a bittersweet&amp;nbsp;departure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WOW&lt;/span&gt;, I have had an amazing experience sharing this time with&amp;nbsp;you!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Problem of Pain</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/04/2011-04-13-problem-of-pain/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-13T04:07:21-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-04-13:blog/2011/04/2011-04-13-problem-of-pain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The reason why pain exists, is to teach the meaning of joy. For those
who know much pain, also understand happiness.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Rainy Days</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/03/2011-03-14-rainy-days/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-14T13:04:47-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-03-14:blog/2011/03/2011-03-14-rainy-days/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;雨點下眼睛風雨在這裡&amp;nbsp;足以不能看到一直往前&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rainy Days 我只有你
Fade Away&amp;nbsp;我的感覺&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我難過又過錯&amp;nbsp;妳到死的錯過&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;別人不能明白閔&amp;nbsp;把故事复述一遍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Love as a Gift</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/03/2011-03-10-love-as-a-gift/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-10T21:02:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-03-10:blog/2011/03/2011-03-10-love-as-a-gift/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the proper aim of giving is to put the recipient in a state where
she no longer needs our gift. Thus a heavy task is laid upon this
gift.**It must work towards it’s own abdication.**&amp;nbsp;We must aim at
making ourselves&amp;nbsp;superfluous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Clive Staples&amp;nbsp;Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Not Giving Up</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2010/11/2010-11-28-giving-up/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-28T11:34:53-08:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2010-11-28:blog/2010/11/2010-11-28-giving-up/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
You either give up, or burn out. Regardless, I&amp;#8217;m going to act like
neither are possibilities.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Gasworks HDR</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2010/06/2010-06-26-gasworks-hdr-so-i-spent-a-lot-of-time-this/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-26T05:13:12-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2010-06-26:blog/2010/06/2010-06-26-gasworks-hdr-so-i-spent-a-lot-of-time-this/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gasworks &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I spent a lot of time this summer reading up on different photography
techniques. One in particular which I have always wanted to be good at
was &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt;. But &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt; is hard, and I&amp;#8217;ve never been able to produce an image
that I felt was good enough to show to anyone&amp;nbsp;else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people who don&amp;#8217;t know what &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt; is, it stands for High Dynamic Range.
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt; takes multiple pictures with different exposures (brightnesses), so
that it can capture all the dark and light areas of an image and merges
them into a single image which carries all the information of the scene.
This bypasses a limitation of digital cameras, because unlike our eyes
which can adjust to capture light at different levels of exposure, a
digital camera can only open and close the shutter once to capture the
full depth of an image. However, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt; can be difficult because processing
an image can end up looking unrealistic and blending exposures comes
with its own&amp;nbsp;hardships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after a lot of failed attempts, I finally came upon a good
opportunity to shoot an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt;, and I gave it my best try.&amp;nbsp;I was at
Gasworks Park near the University of Washington campus, and my friend
was commenting about how I should take a picture of the skies. When I
saw what she was pointing at, I realized that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be able to
shoot it with one exposure, so I strapped the camera around my wrist and
made an attempt to shoot a handheld &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDR&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you like&amp;nbsp;it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="gasworks" src="http://sanghan.me/img/tumblr/tumblr_l4mfa09L8T1qbyrnao1_1280.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Seattle</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2010/06/2010-06-24-seattle/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-24T16:38:37-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2010-06-24:blog/2010/06/2010-06-24-seattle/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had an awesome time in Washington. Pictures to come&amp;nbsp;soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>