<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My Photoelectric Blog</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sanghan.me/feeds/articles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sanghan.me/</id><updated>2014-05-04T23:24:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>New Beginnings</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2014/05/new_beginnings/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-04T23:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2014-05-04:blog/2014/05/new_beginnings/</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
Anything you see below this is old news&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the end of 2011, I had stopped blogging. I had created
a photography website using wordpress and was trying to
make a living for myself as any recent college graduate&amp;nbsp;would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I didn&amp;#8217;t go to school in photography, I had studied chemistry.
But upon realizing the difficulties associated with getting any work
with only an undergrad education, I chose photography since I was good
at it, and I had some experience doing it professionally. I also was
preparing ultimately to go study medicine, and it was my 2nd year of
having gone through the application&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
But something happened&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a job in Santa Barbara in fabricating the next generation of
photonic. It was a real job, the technology was something lost during the
dotcom bubble, but now at resurgence of cloud computing and the demand of
our telecommunications infrastructure. It was something I believed in,
information travling at the speed of light through optical fiber, and
satisfied that itch for uncovering new and novel ideas, so I took&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve learned a lot. So I&amp;#8217;ve decided to start blogging again.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the content below this was generated from my old blog. I was able to
write a program that scraped my old posts through the tumblr &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; and convert
it into reStructuredText. This new blog is now generated by the pelican blogging
engine which I&amp;#8217;ve customized to fit my needs. I had to rewrite some of the
blogging engine as well as rewrite entire plugins due to compatability
reasons between Python 3 &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; 2, or because I just for the fun of&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy and follow&amp;nbsp;along.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="beginning"></category><category term=""></category></entry></feed>