<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My Photoelectric Blog</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sanghan.me/feeds/articles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sanghan.me/</id><updated>2014-05-04T23:24:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>A New Beginning</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2014/05/a_new_beginning/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-04T23:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2014-05-04:blog/2014/05/a_new_beginning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="anything-you-see-below-this-is-old-news"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Anything you see below this is old&amp;nbsp;news&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="photoshoot" src="http://sanghan.me/img/photoshoot.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the end of 2011, I stopped blogging. I had created
a photography website using wordpress and was trying to
make a living as any recent graduate would. I chose photography
because I was good at it, and I had experience shooting with
some &lt;span class="target" id="professional-photographers"&gt;professional photographers&lt;/span&gt; in the san diego&amp;nbsp;area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
However, I didn&amp;#8217;t go to school in photography, I had studied chemistry.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But upon realizing the difficulties associated with work in science
with only an undergrad education, I chose photography. I was ultimately to
study medicine, and it was my 2nd attempt at that crazy application&amp;nbsp;cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="chemistry" src="http://sanghan.me/img/chemistry.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
But something happened&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-job-new-world"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Job New&amp;nbsp;World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a job in Santa Barbara in engineering the next generation of
photonic switches. It was a real job, the technology was a relic lost during the
dotcom bubble, where many tech companies perished and crashed from the burst.
But now at resurgence of cloud computing and the demand of on the backbone
of the fiber-optic infrastructure some companies were starting to hire again.
It was something I believed in, information travling at the
speed of light through optical fiber, and was satisfying that itch
for uncovering new and novel ways of doing things, so I took the job and
didn&amp;#8217;t look&amp;nbsp;back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve learned a lot. So I&amp;#8217;ve decided to start blogging again.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-light-quanta-blog"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Light Quanta&amp;nbsp;Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve decided to name this blog &amp;#8216;A Quanta of Light&amp;#8217;. The reference is to the
photoelectric effect, a discovery made by Physicist Max Plank to
describe the emission of electrons from a metal surface with discrete energies
associated with their wavelengths.
Later in history, Albert Einstein would be awarded with the Nobel Price in
Theoretical Physics for the &amp;quot;Discovery of the Law of the Photoelectric Effect&amp;quot;
albeit his true masterpieces being the works belonging to his Special and General
theory of relativity. But the physics society awarded him with the
Photoelectric Effect because it was something experimentally well documented
and accepted at the time. Much like this blog is a composition of works made
in the&amp;nbsp;past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Photoelectric Effect" src="http://sanghan.me/img/hv.png" style="width: 250px; height: 250px;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
The equation E = ℎ𝜈 - 𝜙 describes the particle nature of light and energy&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the content below this was generated from my old tumblr blog. I was able to
write a program that scraped old posts through the tumblr &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; and convert
it into reStructuredText for parsing. This new blog is now generated by
the pelican blogging engine which I&amp;#8217;ve customized to fit my&amp;nbsp;needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to rewrite some of the blogging engine as well as some plugins due to
compatability issues between Python 2 &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; 3. Maybe I&amp;#8217;ll post about some of the
cool features in a later&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="pull-quote"&gt;
But I&amp;#8217;m excited to start blogging again, and I hope you follow along!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- `professional photographers`_::
http://www.nathanielkamphotography.com --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Beginning"></category></entry></feed>