<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sang Han</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sanghan.me/feeds/photography-tip.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sanghan.me/</id><updated>2011-07-18T21:30:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Photography Tip #3 - White Balance (Color Temperature)</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/07/2011-07-18-photography-tip-3-white-balance-color-temperature/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-07-18T21:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-07-18:blog/2011/07/2011-07-18-photography-tip-3-white-balance-color-temperature/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is a slightly technical tip which will help &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALMOST&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ANYONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
improve their photos. This does not &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; effect people who use
expensive camera gear, but in fact, it is more important for those using
cheaper&amp;nbsp;cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is a picture, can you tell what is wrong with&amp;nbsp;it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" src="/img/20101028_MG_7908.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you don&amp;#8217;t see it yet. But what if I upload the corrected version
of this&amp;nbsp;picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" src="/img/20101028_MG_7908_corrected.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it makes sense. You&amp;#8217;ll probably say, the color is wrong. But more
precisely, it was a problem with white balance or color temperature.
Most &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DSLR&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s which can shoot in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAW&lt;/span&gt; have the advantage of being able to
adjust this setting after you&amp;#8217;ve taken a picture. However, if you&amp;#8217;re
like the many who have a point-and-shoot camera which directly links to
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;JPEG&lt;/span&gt;, you&amp;#8217;ll have to learn how to fix this in camera before you take a
picture. A lot of times understanding white balance makes a big&amp;nbsp;difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is white balance, and how do I fix these on my camera? Just read
a little longer and I&amp;#8217;ll show&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White balance is exactly what is sounds like. It is a standard of
balancing color, which balances white (or grey) &amp;nbsp;to produced correctly
color balanced pictures. Incorrect white balance tends to shift to the
red or the blue of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RGB&lt;/span&gt; color spectrum leaving you with unflattering
shifted images. I&amp;#8217;m baffled at how often, &amp;quot;professional&amp;quot; photographers
who charge for their photos mess up white balance so often. It
is&amp;nbsp;embarrassing, and people will use the &amp;quot;creativity&amp;quot; moniker to justify
their incorrect &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WB&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DON&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;T &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;THESE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PEOPLE&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will seriously own&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you&amp;#8217;ll have to find the white balance option on your camera. It&amp;#8217;ll
look something like&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image2" src="/img/screenWhiteBalance-L.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be multiple options. These are usually the standard drawings
to denote specific white balances. These pictures will make knowing the
white balances &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOO&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MUCH&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EASIER&lt;/span&gt; to understand. White Balance is measured
in Kelvin, which is the temperature of the incident light. But Instead
of memorizing each temperature for each different type of light, you can
just use the&amp;nbsp;pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For normal sunlight situations, the sunlight mode on the far left is
best. For cloudy days, the cloud. And depending on the type of
lightbulb, whether it&amp;#8217;s incandescent or fluorescent, you&amp;#8217;ll use one of
the two blinking light&amp;#8217;s in the center. While using flash, you&amp;#8217;ll use
flash, and the custom white balance is kind of advanced for this type of
tutorial. A lot of newer cameras do a pretty decent job of setting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WB&lt;/span&gt;
automatically. But your eyes are soo much better than the camera, and
setting this manually will ensure you get it right the first&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Color Balance"></category><category term="Color Temperature"></category><category term="Custom"></category><category term="Photography"></category><category term="Tips"></category><category term="WB"></category><category term="White Balance"></category><category term="Sang Han"></category></entry><entry><title>Photography Tip #1 - What Camera Should I Buy?</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/06/2011-06-29-photography-tip-1-what-camera-should-i-buy/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-29T01:29:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-06-29:blog/2011/06/2011-06-29-photography-tip-1-what-camera-should-i-buy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So people have been asking me a lot of questions these days about
photography. One question in particular that I get almost every time is
about which cameras, lenses and other equipment they should purchase.
And a lot of times, I really don&amp;#8217;t feel like I can substantiate this
with an answer without first asking multiple questions myself.&amp;nbsp;Like,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you take pictures of? People? Are you the person among your
group of friends who is always documenting the moment? Does everyone
expect you to be the one uploading and tagging shots on&amp;nbsp;facebook??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landscapes? Are you always bringing your camera when going on that next&amp;nbsp;adventure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art? Is normal photography too mainstream? Are you trying to express
some creative impulse? Do you hang around coffee shops with large framed
glasses and an&amp;nbsp;ipad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of times photography is less about the equipment you own, and more
about the subject that you wish to put on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card (please don&amp;#8217;t
troll me about this). And in fact, you don&amp;#8217;t need to spend ridiculous
amounts of money to have the right camera. Most of the time, the best
camera is the one you&amp;nbsp;own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in order to give an answer to this small rant. I think the question
here is worded incorrectly. Most of the time, people ask about camera
equipment, not because they want to buy something, but because they have
a desire to take better pictures. In this case, I would recommend buying
a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FILM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAMERA&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;Sounds crazy, but it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with point-and-shoot cameras is in the name. The purpose is
to be able to point at a scene and just take a shot. Automation destroys
the desire to learn and makes photography less rewarding. So throwing
yourself into manual settings really opens up a new world for people. If
you can take a decent picture with a film camera, you will probably take
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMAZING&lt;/span&gt; ones in digital. Also, film bodies and lenses are dirt cheap.
You can pick them up from craigslist for &amp;lt;$100 and these used to be top
of the line professional&amp;nbsp;equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you a step in that direction, I would&amp;nbsp;recommend the Canon &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AE&lt;/span&gt;-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" src="/img/D3S_7456-1200.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_AE-1"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_AE-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find these on craigslist and ebay for $50 with a 50mm f/1.8 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FD&lt;/span&gt;
fixed focal length lens. The fixed focal length means that the lens
doesn&amp;#8217;t zoom. But this is more of an advantage. It causes you to think
more about composition and the quality of pictures are outstanding. You
can also purchase a variety of other &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FD&lt;/span&gt; lenses, zoom and fixed for dirt
cheap. You just have to remember one thing, make sure to buy&amp;nbsp;film!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this little rant. It&amp;#8217;s a lot of fun for me to talk to
others about photography. If anyone has any questions at all that they
would like me to answer, let me&amp;nbsp;know!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Camera"></category><category term="Photography Tips"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Canon AE-1"></category></entry></feed>