<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>LightQuanta</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sanghan.me/feeds/quotes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sanghan.me/</id><updated>2014-05-05T23:24:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Digital Universe</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2014/05/digital_universe/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-05T23:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2014-05-05:blog/2014/05/digital_universe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In the digital universe, there are two kinds of bits:
bits that represent structures (differences in space)
and bits that represent sequence (differences in time).
Digital computers - as formalized by Alan Turing, and
developed by John von Neumann - are devices that translate
between these two species of bits according to definite rules.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;George Dyson: Turing's Cathedral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I finished reading &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Turings-Cathedral-Origins-Digital-Universe/dp/1400075998"&gt;Turing's Cathedral&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Turing's Cathedral" src="http://sanghan.me/img/turings_cathedral.jpg" style="width: 420px;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, my interests were focused towards engineering,
and I never really crossed paths with programming or computer science.
Even in my academic life as an undergraduate studying chemistry, the world bound by code
was much of a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book recounts the amazing history that blew up
into the birth of the first computing devices. It was truly fascinating story.
Within the biographical context contained some of my old personal heros like
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman"&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/a&gt;, whose lectures and texts are legendary for any
student of the physial sciences. As well, I picked up some new heroes as well,
like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_von_Neumann"&gt;John von Neumann&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing"&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/a&gt; Namesakes of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Von_Neumann_architecture"&gt;Von Neumann Architecture&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_turing_machine"&gt;Universal Turing Machines&lt;/a&gt;,
still make up the foundations of computation as we know today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I then made up my mind on trying to learn how to write
my own computer programs and see where it would lead me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since then it's been a remarkable year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="alan"></category><category term="turing"></category><category term="dyson"></category><category term="computing"></category></entry></feed>