<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sang Han</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sanghan.me/feeds/rant.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sanghan.me/</id><updated>2011-06-17T06:05:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Photography Rant #1</title><link href="http://sanghan.me/blog/2011/06/2011-06-17-photography-rant-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-17T06:05:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Sang Han</name></author><id>tag:sanghan.me,2011-06-17:blog/2011/06/2011-06-17-photography-rant-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone learns to take good pictures by first taking bad ones. But we
first have to understand that creating the image which puts absolution
to the moment is somewhat of an arduous task. And in fact, most photos
fail to come close to meet this somewhat abstract criterion for a&amp;nbsp;Good&amp;nbsp;Photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although understanding this, most people will never admit to a bad
photo. They come up with cleaver reasonings to vindicate a shot and thus
first place a primal block on their chance of learning from their
mistakes. Working with some of these people, I&amp;#8217;ve heard some pretty good
excuses, most using the &amp;quot;creativity&amp;quot; moniker as a mental force field
against constructive&amp;nbsp;criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we really need to understand is that taking a bad photo is indeed a
good thing. Taking the underexposed 35 degree tilted, center focused
slightly blurry photo with major white balance problems is where most
people start. Eventually, we learn to focus, compose and the desire to
correct ourselves pushes us to the better&amp;nbsp;image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, from the back&amp;nbsp;of a thousand poorly taken photographs spurs an
image redemptive of each past failing exchange. But most of the time, we
just end up taking the shot and moving&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="photography"></category><category term="rant"></category><category term="image"></category><category term="composition"></category></entry></feed>